Finding Aid for Christian T. Feddersen visual materials collection, 1905, 1938 and 1955-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Christian T. Feddersen visual materials collection 1905, 1938 and 1955-1965
Feddersen Christian T.
0.4 linear feet
92171 UA 2
Photographs, 1905 and ca. 1955-1965, and film, 1938, relating to Scandinavian-American activities and organizations in Detroit, Michigan; also photos, 1905, of National Tea Company, a Danish-owned Detroit business.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Christian T. Feddersen (donor no. 4785 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Christian T. Feddersen was born in Kiel, Germany on October 29, 1907. After graduating from the engineering college of Kiel in 1929, he came to Detroit in 1930 where he worked as an engineer. In addition Feddersen was active in various Scandinavian American groups and was the editor and publisher of Scandinavians in Michigan (1968).
The Feddersen collection consists of photographs and a motion picture relating to the organizations and activities of Scandinavian Americans in Michigan. The motion picture is entitled "Scandinavian Midsummer Festival, June 12, 1938." A videocassette has been made of the film.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Apostolic Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Augustana Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Bethlehem Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Business enterprises--Michigan--Detroit.; Churches--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Detroit (Mich.)--Churches.; Detroit Swedish Council.; Ehrling, Sixten.; Festivals.; Fredericks, Marshall M., 1908-1998.; Immanuel Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); National Tea Company (Detroit, Mich.); Lutheran churches--Michigan--Detroit.; Norse Civic Association.; St. John's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Olaf's Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); St. Peter's Danish Evangelical Lutheran Church (Detroit, Mich.); Scandinavian Americans.; Swedish Americans.
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Videotapes.
- Photographs
  - Apri Swedish Male Chorus (Box 1)
  - Churches (Box 1)
  - Danish Brotherhood of America (Box 1)
  - Detroit-Swedish Council, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Ehrling, Sixten, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Fredericks, Marshall M. (Box 1)
  - Groups, identified (Box 1)
  - Groups, unidentified, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Groups, unidentified, men (Box 1)
  - Groups, unidentified, women (Box 1)
  - Individuals, men (Box 1)
  - Individuals, women (Box 1)
  - Individuals, unidentified (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - National Tea Company, Detroit, 1905 (Box 1)
  - Norse Civic Association-anniversary dinners (Box 1)
  - Norse Civic Association-trips, 1961-1965 (Box 1)
  - Scandinavian Symphony Orchestra (Box 1)
  - Scenes, miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Other visual material
  - Motion picture: "Scandinavian Midsummer Festival, June 12, 1938", 10 minute, silent, b&w, 16 mm (Box 1)
  - Videocassette: "Scandinavian Midsummer Festival, June 12, 1938", U-matic transfer from 16mm film, 10 minute, silent, b&w, 3/4 in. (Box 1)